Subtitles by explosiveskull
Sync by GoldenBeard
(CROW CAWS)
NARRATOR:
The year is 517 A.D.,
known as the Dark Ages
and for fucking good reason.
An endless war
between the armies of man
and the creatures of darkness
has raged across Britain.
And in retribution for man's
injustices to creatures,
the immortal witch
Vivienne Nimue
had spread her deadly plague
threatening to wipe mankind
off the face of the Earth.
And so at Pendle Hill,
beneath an ancient oak tree,
King Arthur...
Yes, that King Arthur,
and his powerful
wizard Merlin,
were forced to surrender
to Nimue,
the Queen of Blood.
NIMUE: Well, well, well.
The great King Arthur
comes to Pendle Hill.
NARRATOR: However,
believing man and monster
were never meant
to live in harmony,
Arthur ambushed Nimue.
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
(GROWLS)
(CREATURES SCREECHING)
Betrayed by her most trusted
witch, Ganeida.
No mortal weapon
can harm me.
- Excalibur!
- This is no mortal weapon.
(GROWLS)
NARRATOR: Pissed off,
Nimue unleashed
her deadly plague.
No!
NARRATOR: With one swing
of his legendary sword,
Arthur severed
the Blood Queen's head.
But even that wasn't enough
to stop her.
So he had her cut up
into pieces,
each one locked
in a separate casket.
This is not over.
I am vengeance eternal!
(SCREAMING) No!
NARRATOR:
Sealed with a holy prayer.
Only the words
from a man of God
may break this holy seal.
NARRATOR: Arthur then
ordered his bravest knights
to ride off and bury
her wretched remains
in the far reaches
of the land,
where no one would
ever find her.
Not even the devil himself.
BROOM: (OVER PHONE)
I mean it, son.
No drinking, no fighting,
don't cause a scene.
HELLBOY: Relax, Dad. It's not
my first time in Tijuana.
BROOM: Why do you think
I'm telling you all this?
HELLBOY: Ruiz is my friend.
I just wanna bring him back.
BROOM: Agent Ruiz
is not your friend.
He's someone
you get drunk with.
Three weeks ago,
we sent Ruiz
to investigate
a nest of vampires.
We haven't heard
from him since.
HELLBOY: I'm on it.
A reliable source told me
where I can find him.
BROOM: Call me
when you have him.
HELLBOY: I'm not
going to call you.
BROOM: Just call me!
It's a simple extraction.
Get Ruiz out of there
and bid adios
without making
a big mess. Again.
HELLBOY: I got this, Dad!
You know me,
I have a gentle touch.
Ah, shit! Not again.
(CUMBIA SONG PLAYING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
(CROWD GASPS)
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
CROWD: (CHANTING)
Camazotz! Camazotz! Camazotz!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
Uh... (CHUCKLES)
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
(CROWD GASPS)
Ruiz! Esteban, is that you?
(CAMAZOTZ SPEAKS SPANISH)
CROWD: (CHANTING) Camazotz!
Camazotz! Camazotz! Camazotz!
What's up with
the Camazotz crap, huh?
The B.P.R.D.
sends you down here,
investigate a nest of vampires
and you went silent
about three weeks ago.
I miss you, man.
Come on, I'm here
to bring you back in.
Come on, buddy, let's go.
(CROWD BOOING)
(IN ENGLISH)
So come on, bring me in.
(CROWD CHANTING IN SPANISH)
Okay.
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
(CROWD EXCLAIMS)
Okay. Hey,
what happened to you, man?
What's with the get-up, huh?
Training? Training for what?
(IN ENGLISH)
To kill you!
(CROWD EXCLAIMS)
Okay. Hang on to that for me.
You look good in purple.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS) Ouch!
HELLBOY:
It's been a lot of fun.
Can we get out of here?
- What did they do to you?
- (SNARLS)
(HELLBOY GRUNTS)
Ruiz! Let's have a drink
and talk about this!
You're a good agent!
Buddy, come on.
Come on, don't you remember?
Backyards? Drinking beers
on the porch?
We used to play guitar, man!
You'd play
all that hippy acoustic crap
- and I'd play real music.
- (GROWLS)
- (SNARLS)
- (REFEREE SPEAKS SPANISH)
To hell with this!
(CAMAZOTZ GROWLS)
(CROWD EXCLAIMS)
Hey, I'm sorry, man.
- (CAMAZOTZ GROWLS)
- Are you okay?
Come on, I don't wanna
hurt you, partner.
I know you're in there
somewhere. Talk to me.
(SNARLS) You play the hero,
but I really know
what is under your mask.
Oh, yeah? Is that so?
Let's see what's under yours.
(GROWLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(HISSES)
HELLBOY: Ruiz! Stop this!
(ROARING)
(HELLBOY GRUNTS)
(SCREECHES)
(SCREAMS)
No! No!
(HELLBOY PANTING)
Ruiz.
(WEAKLY) I know you...
Anung un Rama.
Your heart beats with rage.
I know which side
you'll choose at the end.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean... I...
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(POP SONG PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING IN SPANISH)
(WINCES)
(GROANS)
That's okay, little guy.
You're just doing
what you're doing.
I'm not judging.
AGENT STRODE: Hellboy.
No, it's Josh.
People confuse us
all the time.
AGENT STRODE:
Come on, we gotta go.
How did you find me?
AGENT STRODE: Twitter.
You don't exactly blend.
Look, sorry about Ruiz,
but we gotta take you back.
HELLBOY: You can try!
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Come on, big guy. Easy.
We're just following orders.
He wants you back.
The old man sent you?
All he told us
is its important.
We need to go.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(IN ENGLISH)
They're buying.
REPORTER: (ON TV)
Details are still emerging
with regard to the tragic
events in Mexico.
There's very
little information
known about Hellboy
or the secretive agency
that apparently he works for.
(REPORTER CONTINUES
INDISTINCTLY)
(SIGHS)
You missed a spot. May I?
Hey, Dad.
BROOM: My father used to say
shaving was the most important
part of a day.
Separated the gentlemen
from the Philistines.
It takes a real man
to hold a blade
against his own throat
every day
- and not cut the jugular.
- (CHUCKLES)
Grandpa Bruttenholm,
he was all teddy bears
and rainbows.
He was an unrepentant asshole,
but he taught me how to shave.
Like father, like son.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Drowning in tequila
for three weeks
may temporarily
numb the pain.
All it ever really does is
exacerbate your sorrows
and the state of your liver.
I know you're upset
about Agent Ruiz,
but it's part of the job.
Everyone here knows that.
Job didn't kill him, I did.
And I buried him
16 feet under the earth
right by the chapel
of the Virgin Guadalupe,
just to make it proper.
He had become unholy,
a vampyre,
a creature of darkness
beyond salvation.
A creature of darkness
beyond salvation?
You mean, we don't all just
deserve a little
gentle horn shave
every now and then?
You're different.
You always have been.
If my face could talk,
it would disagree with you.
I think
it's a beautiful face.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(IN ENGLISH) The end is coming.
The end of what?
I don't know.
Those were Ruiz's last words.
That and something
about Anung nun...
Does it ring any bells?
Nah. Apocalyptic mutterings.
Now there...
Don't you look handsome!
I'm gonna take your word
for that, Pops.
Why'd you
bring me back, anyway?
Don't tell me
it's 'cause you miss me.
Do you recall
the Osiris Club?
Oh, yeah.
Strip joint in Jersey.
No, the other one.
The British occult society
formed in 1866
by the ranking members
of the Heliopic Brotherhood
of Ra.
Ra? I met Ra once
in the underworld.
He's a close-talker.
You know, like us, they fight
against the forces of darkness
and our organizations have
a long-standing relationship.
They're old friends of mine.
And they've requested
your assistance
with a giant problem.
- Oh, yeah? What's that?
- Giants.
(LAUGHS)
GRUAGACH: Hellboy stole
the life I might've had.
Banished me
into an existence of misery.
I now only live to kill him.
BABA YAGA: I too have suffered
at Hellboy's hands,
so I know your pain.
I felt yours,
so I summoned you here.
(GRUAGACH GROWLS)
I will guide you to a witch,
Vivienne Nimue,
cut to pieces
but alive and waiting.
Restore her!
She will make you
powerful again
so you can have
your vengeance.
- GRUAGACH: I thank you.
- This is not going to be easy.
GRUAGACH: Maybe not.
But to be whole again,
I can do it.
(BABA YAGA SCOFFS)
Go now.
GRUAGACH: I don't get it.
What's in it for you?
(GROWLS) That is no concern
of yours, beast!
In the end,
I'll have my way
and Hellboy will pay
what he owes.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Your guest, m'lord.
Hellboy, welcome.
Lord Adam Glaren.
And may I introduce
my associates,
Dr. Edwin Carp
and August Swain.
HELLBOY: Hi.
You guys ever been
to the Osiris Club in Jersey?
It's like this,
but just with strippers.
May I?
Does it do
anything special?
Yeah, it smashes things
real good.
We are so very glad
you accepted our invitation.
- Wasn't really my choice.
- Ah.
Yes. The Professor.
Your father and I go back
a long way.
Yeah, I heard.
The Osiris Club has been long
dedicated to preserving
the secret history
of Great Britain.
It affords us
certain insights
- into individuals such as yourself.
- (CHUCKLES)
SWAIN: We've also given
vital counsel
to your B.P.R.D.
on occasion.
HELLBOY: Look, maybe we could
just get on with it.
Unless you flew me
halfway around the world
just so that we could, uh,
have a little history lesson.
Perhaps we should
just show you.
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
Secret door.
SWAIN: Giants once dominated
the British Isles.
Vile, loathsome creatures.
As likely to eat you
as look at you.
They've always
been a problem.
Bodies buried
all over England.
It's a curious feature
of giants
that they occasionally rise
from their graves
and wreak havoc.
And when they do,
we organize a hunt.
- The wild hunt.
- HELLBOY: Oh, catchy.
And I thought
I had a big head.
Clearly, you guys
are old pros at this.
Why do you need me
to help you kill a giant?
Three giants, actually.
One, we can handle,
perhaps even two.
But three, that's
a different matter altogether.
This particular trio
is terrorizing the New Forest.
Sucking on the bones of anyone
unlucky enough
to fall foul of them.
The marrow, you see.
They can't get enough.
- Hmm.
- So, if any were to reach
a population center...
It's Miller time. (CHUCKLES)
LORD GLAREN:
This is not a task
to be taken lightly, Hellboy.
These are Gigantum Mortis.
Very unpleasant.
Just ask your father.
Trevor was a guest
of the hunt,
- when we took one down in '43.
- Uh-huh.
I always knew Dad aged well,
but you guys...
Picture looks like
it was taken yesterday.
LADY HATTON:
There's a reason for that.
The phenomenon
you so rightly observed
was the byproduct of a seance
the four of us, along with
your Professor Broom,
were involved in
just before the war.
Allow me to introduce
our resident seer,
Lady Elizabeth Hatton.
The spirit I made
contact with that night
was exceptionally powerful.
It warned us
that something was coming.
Something
that would end mankind.
And that we'd been chosen
to seek it out and destroy it.
Ever since,
we've aged at a snail's pace
in order to fulfill
that mission
no matter how long it took.
Okay. And this thing
you're worried about,
did it show up?
Oh, yes.
You did.
I was there the night
that you came into the world.
World War II
was coming to an end.
Germany was all but defeated.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(THUNDER BOOMING)
But the Nazis still had
one last trick
up their sleeve.
They turned to the infamous
necromancer Grigori Rasputin.
On an island
off the coast of Scotland,
they gathered to invoke
an ancient occult ritual...
(CHANTING IN RUSSIAN)
...intended to turn
the tide of war
back in Germany's favor.
(CONTINUES CHANTING)
(SCREAMS)
LADY HATTON:
But something went wrong.
The ritual didn't turn out
quite as they planned.
(SPEAKS GERMAN)
(GUNS COCKING)
- (GUN FIRES)
- (SCREAMS)
LADY HATTON: Fortunately,
legendary Nazi hunter
the Lobster arrived...
(SPEAKS GERMAN)
LADY HATTON: ...leading
the allies on a daring raid.
Goodbye.
(GROANS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Here, so the devil knows
who sent you.
(SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
- (SIZZLING)
- (SCREAMING)
As for the rest of you
goose-stepping bastards,
beware of my claw
for I have come
to inflict justice
on all of you.
LADY HATTON:
Professor Broom and myself
were working with the allies
at the time.
With his knowledge
of the occult
and my gift of foresight,
we led a secret mission
to the island
to kill whatever abomination
was summoned
from the depths of hell
that night.
- (RUMBLING)
- (GUNS COCKING)
Hold it!
I'll take it from here.
LADY HATTON:
Instead, we found you.
LADY HATTON: Your father
never told you, did he?
Why he was really there
that night?
Must've slipped his mind.
Rasputin brought you
in the world as a weapon.
With patience
and understanding,
Broom turned that weapon
into a force for good.
"Patience and understanding."
You sure we're talking
about the same guy?
He saw something in you
that the rest of us could not.
And he raised you
as his own son.
You should get some rest,
Hellboy.
The hunt will assemble
at dawn.
HELLBOY: So I'm devil spawn
and a Nazi.
Great. Thanks, Dad.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
- (SHATTERS)
- Oh, come on!
(BELL TOLLING)
(GROWLING)
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(POUNDING ON DOOR CONTINUES)
(POUNDING CONTINUES)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(ROARS)
- Where is it, monk?
- (WHIMPERS)
Come here, you fucking
bastards! (GROWLS)
- (FLESH RIPPING)
- (WHIMPERING)
- Come here! Have you got it?
- (MONKS SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
I wonder, does screaming
break your
vow of silence, brother?
You know what I'm looking for.
Where is it?
(SNARLING)
Show me!
- Come on!
- (MONK GASPS)
(MONK WHIMPERING)
(GRUAGACH GROWLS)
Come here, monk!
(MONK GRUNTING)
(SNORTS)
- (SIZZLING)
- (YELLING)
- I fuckin' hate iron!
- (WHIMPERING)
Open it.
Speak the words.
You know only the words
from a man of God
can break the seal.
- (WHIMPERING)
- Fucking open it!
(GROWLS)
Have I gotta do
everything meself?
- (MONK GROANING)
- Gobshite.
(CHANTS LATIN IN MONK'S VOICE)
(IN ENGLISH)
Welcome back, Your Majesty.
What, are we trick-or-treating
or hunting giants?
Tradition. To honor the brave
huntsmen who've come before.
HELLBOY: And the pig stickers?
LORD GLAREN:
Another tradition.
Used by giant slayers
throughout the ages.
With a few modern
modifications, of course.
Five times as potent
- as an electric chair.
- Mmm.
Not enough to kill a giant,
mind you. But, uh, still,
quite handy in subduing the creatures.
Would you care for one?
Oh, it's all right,
I got traditions of my own.
Oh, God. I don't have to
wear the hat, do I?
(CHUCKLING) No.
We're very well aware
of your distaste for horns.
It's my honor,
as master of the hunt,
to wear the headdress.
- Mmm.
- (HORSE WHINNIES)
And here we are.
Long Shadow.
HELLBOY: Don't you have a jeep
or a motorcycle or something?
That wouldn't be
very sporting now, would it?
He'll bring you home safely.
For the record,
this wasn't my idea.
(HORSE WHINNIES)
Three sets of tracks.
Just as Lady Hatton foretold.
I count four bodies.
Parts of them, anyway.
- LORD GLAREN: They'll be back.
- What makes you so sure?
Giants don't leave
food behind.
The tracks are heading north,
toward the river.
This is where
we'll make our stand.
They'll use the bridge
to cross.
We can take up positions
in the brush on either side.
Yeah, seems like a perfect
spot for an ambush.
My thoughts exactly.
(SCREAMS)
(HORSE WHINNIES)
- (GRUNTING)
- (INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
- HUNTSMAN 1: Let's get him!
- HUNTSMAN 2: Take him!
(SCREAMING)
After him!
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
LORD GLAREN:
Bring him down!
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
Did you really think
we needed your help
to kill something we've been
hunting for centuries?
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(SCREAMING)
LORD GLAREN:
We will never allow the devil
to sit on the throne
of England.
It would usher
in the apocalypse.
(HELLBOY SCREAMING)
I must confess
when Lady Hatton
first told me
about her vision
and what needed to be done
I was hesitant.
Broom was so certain
of your potential
and you have done
so much good.
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
- (GROANING)
But fate is a fickle beast.
And now I must do
what your father should have
done those many years ago.
No.
If it's any consolation,
your head will make
a wonderful addition
to our gallery.
(GROWLING)
(HUNTSMEN SCREAMING)
(HORN BLARING)
(MUSIC PLAYING ON TV)
- Oh, Jill!
- GIRLS: You are going down!
WOMAN: Oh, I thought it was
the same toe.
(THUDDING)
You have no idea
how many I had to kill.
I'll have you playing Twister
in no time.
Sorry, too soon.
And soon you shall reap
the reward for your efforts.
I didn't know if you'd be
hungry or what, you know.
A thousand years in a box
and I'd be starving. (LAUGHS)
You wouldn't believe
what people
throw away
these days. Cookie!
Revenge is the only sustenance
I require.
Look at this.
A world ravaged by war
and poverty
led by feckless fear mongers.
They've replaced swords with
singing competitions.
GRUAGACH: Yeah.
(GRUNTS) Well,
not for much longer.
What about my other hand?
You're certain
you can retrieve it?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah.
And you'll restore me,
as you promised?
Don't worry,
you'll get what's due.
All good things
come to those who wait.
Bring me the last box.
Make me whole again.
And together,
we will baptize this world
in blood.
(PANTING)
(GASPING)
That hurt. Okay.
(FAINT GROWLING)
Huh?
(CRUNCHING IN DISTANCE)
(HUNTSMEN SCREAMING)
HELLBOY: Well, look at that.
I guess you did need my help
after all.
Wait a minute.
I thought there was
supposed to be three.
(GROWLING)
Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa!
(GROANING)
(GROWLS)
(ROARING)
(HELLBOY PANTING)
(SCREAMING)
God, I'm gonna feel that
in the morning. (GRUNTS)
HELLBOY: Come to papa.
Hold still, handsome!
(GIANT SCREAMS)
It's fucking wet in there!
(HELLBOY PANTING)
Hey, pal!
Ugh!
What have you been eating?
(GIANT BELCHES)
Oh, shit, I forgot.
(GROWLING)
Yeah, it's just you
and me now, princess!
(PANTING)
(GIANT GRUMBLES)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
HELLBOY: Is that my Uber?
GIRL: There he is.
- That's him.
- MAN: Let's get him.
(GASPS)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
(PANTING)
Welcome back
to the land of the living.
Hardly a scratch left.
You heal fast.
Where am I?
Bacon, eggs
and black pudding, do ya?
You look like you could use
a proper English breakfast.
Go on, sit down
before you fall down.
How did I get here?
A man with a van.
Actually, four men.
You owe me 300 quid,
by the way.
I'm sorry,
do I know you?
"Beware the Jabberwock,
my son!
"The jaws that bite,
the claws that catch!
- "Beware..."
- "...the Jubjub bird..."
- "...and shun the frumious...
- "...the frumious..."
"...Bandersnatch!"
Alice.
Little Alice Monaghan.
Not so little Alice Monaghan.
(CHUCKLES)
This is what you do now, huh?
You what, you read tea leaves?
You, uh,
you tell people's fortune?
I make use of the gifts
I was given.
Oh, yeah? You let folks
talk to their dead relatives?
For what,
like five bucks a pop?
- More like a tenner.
- (WINCES)
Missed one.
- (ALARM BEEPING)
- Bollocks! (SIGHS)
You'll have to eat
around the burnt bits.
(SIGHS)
And lucky for you, too.
If it weren't for the dead,
I never would've found you.
They keep blathering on.
Especially Mom and Dad.
Oh.
They say hi, by the way.
Sorry. I didn't know.
Why would you?
Maybe if you'd given a flying
fig and checked in on me
- once in the past 20...
- (VOICES WHISPERING)
What? No, he doesn't.
Just let me deal with it.
More dead people?
I told you,
they never shut up.
What are they
telling you now?
They're saying I should kill
you while I have the chance.
You see, they know
what you don't,
that I've got a shotgun
under the table
loaded with angel bones
aimed right at your todger.
(COCKS GUN)
(SIGHS) Seems like everybody
wants me dead nowadays.
They give you a reason?
Only that the end is coming.
And it'll be you
that brings it.
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
Google-translate that,
would you?
(IN ENGLISH)
It's just something that
a friend told me,
you know.
Like a prophecy.
You gonna shoot me or what?
- (CHAIR SCRAPES)
- (GASPING)
The dead might be afraid
of your demon ass,
but I know you better.
Besides, I still owe you one
for saving my life
when I was just a kid.
So, what are we doing
down here?
Avoiding the glass.
(GRUNTS)
- Armed police!
- HELLBOY: Stay here!
ALICE: Jesus Christ!
BROOM: That's my boy.
Dad!
Hello, son.
BROOM: I just don't know why
- you were so angry with me.
- You couldn't have knocked?
Well, I told you,
after we cleaned up
the mess you left behind
with the giants
and you weren't there,
I feared the worst. Thank God
you're all right. Okay?
You know what hurts worse than
being stabbed in the back?
Being stabbed in the back.
Oh, come on.
You can't possibly believe
that I knew the Osiris Club
was plotting
to assassinate you.
You know what
I can't believe?
I can't believe
you showed up on Nazi island
all those years ago
just to kill me.
Yeah, that's right,
I bumped into your old flame,
Lady Hatton.
She, uh, filled me in
on a couple of
the missing pieces
of our family narrative.
Well, if you wanna dig up
my sordid skeletons,
I'll be the first
to hand you a shovel.
But this is not the time,
and there's someone
I wanna introduce
you to, okay?
Major Ben Daimio,
head of Special Ops for M-11.
- M-11?
- My son.
I thought you guys disbanded
after the war.
And I thought
we were supposed to be
fighting monsters,
not working with them.
Who you calling monster, pal?
You look in the mirror
recently, Scarface?
- Is that meant to be humor?
- Maybe.
My therapist does say
that I rely on jokes
as a way to normalize.
Normalize, right.
Good luck with that.
(GROWLS)
So glad to see you two
are getting along.
Since this is on British soil,
it'll be a joint operation.
Please, I don't need any help
kicking the dentures out of
the Osiris Club, all right?
I got this.
No, this is bigger
than you know.
St. Sebastian's
has been attacked
and a relic was stolen.
Thought to be one
of the Nimue Caskets.
Nim-who?
Vivienne Nimue.
Also known as the Blood Queen.
An immortal
fifth century sorceress.
Amongst her powers,
she has a plague
that almost wiped Britain
off the map.
And this time
it could be the world.
King Arthur himself
took care of that monster.
He used Excalibur
to dismember her,
then locked the pieces
in caskets
and hid them
throughout the country.
Very impressive, Major.
The Osiris Club discovered one
in the '30s
and kept it as part
of their permanent collection.
Great. So we go back
to the Osiris Club,
we find this casket,
we figure out whoever's
trying to Humpty Dumpty
this Blood Queen back together
and we get a little payback
while we're at it.
Payback?
This isn't about revenge.
For me, it is.
Once the casket is secure,
you'll be
on the first flight out.
The Bureau can put you back
in your cage.
HELLBOY: My cage?
My cage!
I'm gonna ask specifically
that you clean my sawdust.
Can't wait till you smell
demon shit, pal!
ALICE: They tell me
you're the man in charge.
- DAIMIO: What's this?
- A bill for damages.
A million pounds?
For a few broken windows?
You've gotta factor
in the emotional trauma.
I'm sorry,
who are you again?
I'm the girl who saved
Hellboy. Who the hell are you?
Yeah, I wanted to thank you
for that, by the way.
So, she's what,
your bodyguard?
Fucking right I am.
So let's go.
This is a military operation!
Not a carnival sideshow.
Alice is the only person
that I trust, all right?
So, you want me,
she comes with.
Here, your new toy.
Do what you have to do.
I'm going back to HQ
and try to locate
the rest of the Blood Queen.
Good luck, hmm?
Professor.
What about the girl?
Alice? She's a powerful
spirit medium.
Take her with you. We need
all the help we can get.
All right, we're done here!
Let's move it out!
Well, aren't you
gonna open it?
Hmm?
That's mega.
HELLBOY: He's probably
overcompensating
'cause he's not my real dad.
That's some present.
Some dads get
their kids LEGOs.
- (BUZZING SOUND)
- (GASPS)
What's wrong?
- What's wrong?
- Psychic migraine.
It's like a car crash
in my head.
Something terrible
happened here.
(BRAKES SQUEAL)
Stay here. Don't move.
- (GASPS)
- (DISTANT SCREAMING)
Oh, God.
- Hold. Move on my command.
- HELLBOY: What?
Can we go in now?
For fuck's sake, help him!
Can't you hear him screaming?
Alice.
(SCREAMS ECHOING)
(ALICE GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PANTING)
(FAINT RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
DAIMIO: What is that sound?
(SCREAMS ECHOING)
HELLBOY: It's Lady Hatton.
The psychic
you were telling us about?
Clearly, she wasn't
psychic enough.
Alice, picking up anything?
Her spirit's still with us.
HELLBOY: You think
you can make contact?
Figure out what the hell
happened here?
You might wanna leave, Major.
This kind of thing
isn't pretty.
And miss all the fun?
Not a chance.
Lady Hatton,
can you hear me?
(SIGHS)
Lady Hatton...
(RUMBLING STOPS)
Well, I'll be fucked.
Nimue, she has returned.
Yeah, we know that.
Uh, is that why
Osiris tried to kill me?
Man will fall
to her darkness.
Those who call
the shadows home
will rise again.
Okay.
I'd appreciate a prophecy with
smaller and more relatable stakes.
The Queen must
never find a king!
When Nimue is whole again,
then your true destiny
will be revealed.
This I have seen.
Only then will...
Only then will what?
Hey, hey! Hey!
You're just getting
to the good part!
It's still here!
(SCREAMING)
(ALICE COUGHING)
- DAIMIO: Are you all right?
- ALICE: No.
A lady just came out of
my fucking mouth!
- (GROWLING IN DISTANCE)
- (POUNDING)
Stay with her.
(LOUD POUNDING SOUND)
GRUAGACH: Oh, fuck!
I know you.
(GROWLS)
HELLBOY: Is that an arm?
Fucking let me go!
Oh, that's disgusting!
Didn't your mother
ever tell you
you shouldn't play
with dead things!
GRUAGACH: My Queen, help me!
I'm not ready yet!
My Queen!
(LOW GROWLING)
NIMUE: Fascinating.
Never have I seen a creature
quite like you.
Nimue.
Such power,
such glorious potential.
There is no reason for us
to be enemies,
when we can be
so much more.
They fear us.
They call us monsters.
We yearn for the same day,
when we are not reviled but
lauded as heroes.
Seed by seed,
tree by tree,
stone by stone,
we'll replant Eden together.
What happens next,
only the fates decide.
DAIMIO: Hellboy!
(GRUNTS)
You fucking prick!
I missed, didn't I?
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Hey! Tell me
you got the bastard.
We pursued. The damn thing
was just too fast.
We didn't even get
a proper look at it.
HELLBOY: That ugly pig-faced
son of a bitch.
But you did,
didn't you?
You know what's going on here,
so I strongly suggest
you start talking.
It was the Gruagach.
- The what?
- Are you sure?
Yeah. I'd never forget
a face like that.
What's a Gruagach?
HELLBOY: We first
crossed paths years ago.
Alice was just
a baby at the time,
and fairies loved
to steal babies.
It's like living
in a nightmare
we can't wake up from.
HELLBOY: Who knows why, but when they
do manage to get their hands on one,
they leave a changeling in
its place to pass for human.
She looks the same, but...
I can't explain it.
That's not my daughter.
(CHUCKLING) Oh, look at you.
Alice, aren't you
the cutest little baby?
- (BABBLING)
- (BABY COOING)
Your mom
and your dad are, uh,
well, worried that you've
been acting strange.
It's okay.
Uncle Hellboy is here.
And he's got just the thing
for that.
(FUSSING)
(CRYING)
Yeah, that's what I thought,
you little bastard!
Ah, Jesus!
What are you doing?
Iron. They hate the stuff.
- (GRUNTING)
- (CONTINUES CRYING)
(SCREAMS)
Let me go!
Let me go! Ahh!
This is child abuse!
I'm a little baby,
you big fuck!
(GRUNTS)
- FATHER: It's disgusting!
- MOTHER: What is that thing?
Didn't get!
Fuck off!
(YELPS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (SIZZLING)
It hurts! It hurts!
I promise! I promise!
The fairies
will return her!
I swear!
Just fucking let me go!
Yeah, I'd love to
take your word for it.
But you know what?
There's one problem,
I'm just not stupid!
(SPITS)
- (SCREAMS)
- GRUAGACH: Twat!
You slippery little bastard!
Listen!
You better bring these people
back their baby
or I'm coming
to get her myself!
And then you
and your fairy friends
are gonna be sorry!
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(CLOCK TICKING)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
About goddamn time.
- (BABY COOS)
- MOTHER: Alice!
- Oh, my God. She's back.
- (FAIRY SCREECHES)
HELLBOY: This better be
a clean diaper,
or I'm coming after you!
FATHER: Oh, wee Alice.
ALICE: Guess I couldn't
avoid him forever.
Destiny always has a way
of bringing things
full circle.
HELLBOY: Destiny.
Stupid word
for "coincidence."
Don't talk shit about fate.
She's a vindictive bitch.
We carry every sin committed
in our bloodlines.
Blood Queen said
pretty much the same thing.
So, that's what
this is all about?
Some fairy tale wanker
you pissed off
is now looking for revenge?
And he's now using
the Blood Queen to get it.
I don't know about that.
Maybe she's using him.
And how's that?
This Arthur comes along,
chops her up
into little pieces,
buries her in boxes?
Maybe she just wants
monsters to come out
from the shadows
and live again.
Great, so she gets another
shot at wiping out mankind.
Hey, hey, hey.
We don't know that about her.
Not for sure.
Collect our men. I'm taking
them back to London HQ.
(EXHALES)
(MATCH STRIKES)
HAG 1: O night, faithful
preserver of mysteries.
(CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(NIMUE GROANING)
HAG 2: And ye bright
stars and moon.
Succeed the fires
of hateful day.
(CHANTING)
(SCREAMS)
Careful, you slags!
The pain is fleeting
compared to 1,500 years
locked in a box.
I only live to serve,
my Queen.
You only serve
to get your revenge
against this Hellboy.
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
Why is he
so important to you?
(ROARS) He burnt me with iron
and cursed me
to a world of shame.
- I could've been a person.
- (NIMUE GROANING)
Not this wasted,
wandering thing.
(GROANS)
I could've had a real life,
filled with light
and happiness. (SNORTS)
Hellboy stole that from me.
Poor creature.
Lust for vengeance has
made us both blind with rage.
Nimue, Queen of Witches.
Nimue who lives.
(GROANING)
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
Nimue, who can never die.
(NECK CRACKS)
(EXHALES)
But now,
I see a new path
laid out before me,
one that would lead
to far greater glory.
- And your Hellboy is the key.
- Hellboy? But...
Where are we going with this?
I don't... I don't understand.
You will. (PANTING)
But first,
we must complete
one final task.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- HELLBOY: Fish 'n chips shop?
- DAIMIO: We're here.
HELLBOY: This is it?
Were you expecting a sign that
says "Secret Headquarters"?
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (BELL JINGLES)
Come on.
Mrs. Harker.
Hello.
Whoa, I thought it smelled
bad on the outside.
I'll let you two take it
from here. I'm leaving.
And you,
don't go anywhere.
Last thing I need
is some freak
wandering around
scaring the locals.
- ALICE: Where's he going?
- (BELL JINGLES)
Haven't we got to be
saving the world or something?
Uh... (WHISPERS)
He's an asshole.
MRS. HARKER: Oi.
I need some ID, love.
Are you serious?
Rules are rules,
I'm afraid.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Whoa. Mmm. Now I've been
to purgatory and hell.
AGENT STRODE: It was
an old bomb shelter
that was refurbished
after the war.
Refurbished?
You call this refurbished?
Oh, good, you're here!
This is all we got
on Nimue so far.
We're fine.
Thank you for asking.
Your friends at Osiris,
not so much.
BROOM: No two stories
are alike,
but everything
seems to suggest
she won't get her full powers
until she's
completely restored.
Hey, hey, did you hear me?
All your friends are dead!
And there'll be
a lot more dead
if we don't find her.
So perhaps you two
would like to grab a book,
do some research,
maybe find out where she is,
so we can bury her
before she buries us.
Great. Homework. (GROANS)
No wonder Daimio took off.
(HORN BLARING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
DAIMIO: Agent Daimio, M-11.
Is the package ready?
MAN: Sir, almost.
DAIMIO: You're sure
this is going to work?
A lot of people have
tried to kill him already.
Not with something
like this they didn't.
It's cast from Judas Silver
mixed with the blood
of Saint Dominic,
blessed by
the Holy Father himself.
It will work,
I assure you.
Assuming you've actually
got to use it.
I mean, who's to say
this bloke's not on the level?
Do you know what I did
before joining the service?
I was an actuary.
I assessed risk
based on a series of complex
mathematical equations.
You see, people lie,
but numbers don't.
And from where I stand,
Hellboy doesn't add up.
The monster inside him
cannot be denied.
It's not personal,
it's just maths.
So, yeah, can't see
letting him live.
Make sure it's a kill shot.
Either the heart or the brain.
The heart it is.
Hellboy's brain
is too small a target.
HELLBOY: Why does this book
have so many words?
Let's say we find Nimue, huh?
Let's say we find her.
(GRUNTS)
Then what?
Well, with a righteous fury
and a mighty fist,
you'll smite her down.
Oh, now,
come on, Hellboy,
take your feet off
Churchill's desk, will you?
ALICE: Whoa. Wicked.
Then what?
Then we make sure she doesn't
come back for the sequel.
Then what?
Then the world
will keep on spinning
and we'll have
another cup of tea.
And then...
(HUMMING)
...what?
What are you on about?
Just answer the question.
And then what? Well, we fight
our next foe. It's what we do.
- And then what?
- Guys.
And then... What?
You have something
to say, say it.
Your moral high ground is
founded on a pile of bullshit.
This is the B.P.R.D.
We're the line in the sand.
That's the thing
about sand,
you can always draw
another line.
- Guys!
- BROOM: If we weren't here,
this would be Satan's
holiday home.
You know, maybe if humans
weren't so keen
on killing witches
and demons and such,
the witches
and demons and such
wouldn't be so keen
on killing humans.
That's a false equivalence
and you know it.
HELLBOY: There's gotta be
another way.
The answer
to every threat we face
cannot be annihilation.
There's gotta be
a world where monsters
don't have to hide
in the shadows,
where they don't have to live
in fear. Where monsters...
Has she got to you? Nimue,
she got to you
with her perfumed words
and her perky breasts?
- So stupid!
- BROOM: Oh!
I'm not even
talking about her!
Then who?
We face every mystical and
metaphysical threat there is,
and yet you take me in. Why?
You were sent to kill me.
What changed your mind?
You did.
You gave me a gun
on my tenth birthday!
You sent me into
the Wildungen forest
to hunt a pack
of wild hill trolls!
Here we go again.
No, we didn't play
Snakes and Ladders.
We didn't play Go Fish.
I didn't coach you
in football or baseball.
You made me a goddamn weapon.
I just wanted to help you
become the best you.
If you, uh, loved me,
maybe you could talk to
some of your human friends
that would want to
see me dead,
rather than unleashing me
to slaughter
my brothers and sisters!
What?
Just solid parenting.
Goddamn humans.
- AUTOMATED VOICE: Going up.
- (GRUMBLES)
(ELEVATOR THUDS)
Going down.
I pushed up!
- Up!
- Going down.
What the fuck?
- Up! Up! Up! Up!
- Down. Down. Down. Down.
Down. Down. Down.
Going down.
(DINGING)
(EXCLAIMING)
(SHOUTING)
- (THUDS)
- (GROANS)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Lower ground.
(GROANS)
(EXHALES)
(HOWLING IN DISTANCE)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(FOOTSTEPS GROW LOUDER)
Baba Yaga.
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
Oh!
(GASPING) Whoa.
Whoa!
(GRUNTS)
Baba? Baba Yaga!
Ah, cut the crap.
I know you're here.
Why'd you summon me?
You wanna play games, huh?
Tell you what,
let's break out the Yahtzee.
Otherwise, I'm not interested.
BABA YAGA: I felt your hunger,
and I have prepared
a feast for you.
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(GURGLES)
Don't you look lovely.
Most think me grotesque.
An old hag with one eye.
Oh, no, not me.
Probably because
you did this to me!
I recall
you trying to raise
Stalin's ghost
from the Necropolis.
I had to do something
to stop you.
So you shot out my eye
and put me in this prison.
You know, I thought
that banishing you
to an adjacent dimension
was, uh,
kinda clever.
Come. Sit.
Eat.
Uh...
Yeah. Quite a spread
for just two people.
We celebrate her return.
Nimue?
(HISSES)
You are correct
to applaud her righteousness.
In her world,
you will be hailed a hero!
They will build statues
of you, 2,000 feet high!
Made from the bones
of your enemies.
That'd take a shit-ton
of bones.
What is for dinner?
Is that a child?
It's just a human child.
(FLIES BUZZING)
(CHAINS CLINKING)
Eat.
- Oh, God!
- (CLATTERING)
So clumsy. Sorry about that.
I gotta go.
Gotta be there
for that resurrection.
Gonna be better
than The Beatles!
BABA YAGA: I can help you.
You can, can't you?
You know where Nimue is,
don't you?
Such nice eyes.
Yellow as piss.
My favorite color.
I want one to replace
what you took from me.
That's not
gonna happen, sister.
Your time
is running out, demon.
Once Nimue's resurrection
is complete,
her plague will strip
the flesh from bodies.
All right,
fine, take it.
Just tell me
where to find Nimue first.
This is a sacred bargain.
Once made,
it cannot be broken.
What, do you want it
in writing?
No need.
Let's seal it
with a kiss.
(BABA YAGA MOANING)
(HELLBOY GROANING)
HELLBOY: How do you have
hair on your tongue?
Go to Pendle Hill.
She will need to
reclaim her blood
in order
to restore her power.
You only have
until midnight.
Which shall it be,
the right
- or the left?
- (GAGGING)
Now, this will hurt a lot.
(GRUNTS)
- You swore!
- You'll get your eye.
Soon as I'm done with it.
We never specified
a time frame.
Should've been more specific.
- (BLADES SWISH)
- (GRUNTS)
- (ROARS)
- (YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
You've been eating children!
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(HELLBOY GRUNTING)
(IN ENGLISH) Go!
Take your eyes
and have them for a while.
(RUMBLING)
But cheat me
and here's my curse,
that you have two eyes
to see the thing
you love most in the world
suffer and die!
(SCREAMS)
(HELLBOY GROANS)
BROOM: So, are you just not
using doors anymore?
- (CONTINUES GROANING)
- Don't keep us in suspense.
I just had a visit
from Baba Yaga.
The Blood Queen's
in Pendle Hill.
(GRUNTS)
We're on a clock!
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Glad to see
you've straightened
your priorities out.
HELLBOY: I'm not taking orders
from you, old man!
I'm just drawing my own line
in the sand!
(EXCLAIMS)
Somebody, please,
get me a mint!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
It has been a long time,
old friend.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYS ON HEADPHONES)
ALICE: This is sick.
Do you know what they did
to the witches at Pendle Hill?
They cut off their tongues,
fed them to maggots
and buried them alive
right there on the spot.
(MUSIC STOPS)
Don't believe everything
you read on the Internet.
ALICE: What did I say?
Ridding the world of evil
is a dirty business.
What's with you
and monsters, anyway?
One of them touch you
funny as a kid?
I've been seeing
freaky shit my whole life,
and if it's
taught me anything,
it's that hate hides behind
the most righteous faces.
Are you seriously gonna
lecture me about faces?
Maybe you think I got
these scars from shaving.
What happened?
I'm not gonna stop asking.
You might as well tell me.
My unit was on
a training exercise in Belize.
One of the local tribal elders
came to us asking for help.
Their village was under attack
by a man-eater.
It would come at night,
carry off its prey.
- (RUSTLING)
- (SOLDIER GRUNTS)
Mostly men,
but sometimes
it was women
and children, too.
(SOLDIER SCREAMING)
Savage. Smart.
Totally without remorse.
All the while
that we were hunting it,
in reality, it was hunting us.
- (ROARS)
- (SCREAMS)
I was the only survivor.
I'm so sorry.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
- (RAPID BEEPING)
- We're coming up on target.
(HELLBOY GRUNTS)
DAIMIO: There's no way
we can land on that hill.
I'll get us up
as close as I can.
Here you go, Queen.
You'll be back to feeling
your amazing old self
in no time.
My life blood sustains you...
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
But now I must reclaim
what is mine.
The others will be here soon.
What about Hellboy?
If he comes, I have
a little surprise in store.
HELLBOY: Come on,
it's almost midnight!
Time's running out.
Wait! Wait!
Just wait!
- (ALICE PANTING)
- (HELLBOY GRUNTS)
I'm not a demon or a soldier.
I'm fucking knackered.
- Just give us a sec.
- HELLBOY: All right.
Let me give you...
(SCREAMING)
A hand!
(HELLBOY YELLS)
Won't anything in this country
stay buried!
(SNARLS)
(GROANS) Not now!
(GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTS)
(WITCHES SCREECHING)
(CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GASPS)
(CONTINUES CHANTING)
(GUNS FIRING)
(GRUNTING)
Hellboy! It's almost midnight.
Go find the Blood Queen.
We can handle this.
She'll spread her plague
if you don't stop her!
There's no time! Go!
Alice, I'm not leaving you.
Go! Stop Nimue!
I'm out.
Stay behind me!
Where the fuck else
am I gonna go?
Goal!
(CONTINUES CHANTING)
(GASPS)
(EXHALES)
At last...
I am reborn.
Yeah, you're looking good,
Your Majesty. (LAUGHS)
(SING-SONG) She's the queen
of the castle. (CHUCKLING)
They're here,
my Queen.
(GROWLING)
(CREATURES GROWLING
AND SNARLING)
GRUAGACH: They've come
from out of the darkness
to celebrate your return.
No more bowing and scraping,
my beloveds.
That is not what I want.
(SNARLING)
I want an army,
long hidden
from the eyes of man.
I want the forgotten people
out of the dark!
Those who have lived in dust,
who have gnawed on dry bones
while dreaming of blood!
That is what I want.
Give me an army like that
and we will make
the daytime world weep!
(CREATURES ROARING)
(TWIG SNAPS)
Well, don't just cower
there like mice.
Step forth.
Ah.
Dear sisters.
How kind of you to grace me
with your presence
after hiding all these years.
Please, Nimue, for me
and my sisters, have mercy.
Ganeida, did you
show me mercy?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(BONES CRACKING)
When Arthur
cut me to pieces
and buried me alive,
where was your mercy then?
- Don't, I beg you!
- Look at you.
Groveling like an animal.
Don't worry, Ganeida,
I won't kill you.
(GASPS)
But you must do something
for me first
to prove
your newfound loyalty.
Take Hellboy to the one
who can show him his destiny.
(GUN FIRES)
Oh, sorry!
Did I interrupt?
Hellboy, you bastard!
(CREATURES SCREECHING
AND ROARING)
(GROANING)
I hope I'm not late
to the party!
(HELLBOY SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
You've arrived
just in time.
ALICE: There's too many.
(GRUNTING)
Get off him!
(DAIMIO GRUNTING)
Behind you!
(SCREECHES)
(WITCH CACKLES)
(DAIMIO YELLS)
(ALICE GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
(DAIMIO GRUNTS)
Where'd you learn
how to do that?
I don't know. Ever since
the fairies took me,
I've been able to do
some weird shit.
Stay behind me.
Where else am I gonna go?
Get us out of here!
- (HELLBOY GROANS)
- GRUAGACH: Know when to wait.
(LAUGHS) Not so fucking
funny now, eh?
My Queen, restore me now!
Let me finish him!
Not just yet.
But you swore...
- Ow!
- Mind your tongue, pig.
- Move it.
- (HELLBOY GRUNTING)
NIMUE: Get in.
Hey.
HELLBOY: Where do you
think you're going?
To give birth to a new world!
Yeah, by killing
a lot of innocent people!
(GROANS)
Why do you fight for those
who hate and fear you?
All I wanted was revenge,
until I saw you.
You can usher
in the apocalypse.
Out of the ashes,
a new Eden will emerge.
Leave these frail,
pathetic humans behind.
Be my king. And be revered
for who you really are.
We belong together,
you and I.
We do! But it's not
gonna work, you know,
'cause I'm a Capricorn
and you're fucking nuts!
A demon sleeps inside you,
and I will waken it.
ALICE: Hellboy! Hellboy!
(GASPS)
NIMUE: Even if I have to
take away everything
and everyone
you've ever loved.
HELLBOY: I got you, kid.
Congratulations,
the Blood Queen has all her powers now.
GANEIDA: Don't touch it!
It'll only make it
spread faster.
(YELLING)
You got three seconds
to make this right!
(GAGGING) I can't.
Three.
GANEIDA:
Nimue's power is too strong.
HELLBOY: Two.
There is one who can help you
from the Old World.
HELLBOY: Where?
You're not seriously
gonna listen to her!
She could be leading us
straight into a trap!
- (HELLBOY GRUNTS)
- You can save your friend.
HELLBOY: We don't have a choice.
GANEIDA: Go to Black Fin.
High atop the cliffs
there's an old goat path
hidden in the rocks.
The way is treacherous,
but you must follow it
until you can go no further.
There, you'll find a passage
into the bowels of the Earth,
in a cave.
HELLBOY: This way, Daimio.
GANEIDA: The one
you seek is there.
Merlin the Wise.
Wizard to kings,
and king of fools.
Cursed to live forever
buried in a hole
for allowing Arthur
to betray the truce.
- (THUD)
- (HELLBOY GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Have you finally come
to claim my soul?
That's the other guy.
Come on!
My friend's been poisoned,
and we were told
that you can help!
I have seen this before.
This is Nimue's work.
You cannot underestimate
this witch.
She is evil incarnate.
There's still a chance
if we act quickly.
But you must promise me
something in return.
That you will do
whatever is necessary
to destroy Nimue,
no matter the cost.
I can damn well guarantee it.
(MERLIN CHANTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(EXCLAIMS)
(SCREAMING)
(CONTINUES CHANTING)
(COUGHING)
DAIMIO: Should we be worried
about where that's going?
Hey.
Welcome back.
Who's the new guy?
HELLBOY: You wouldn't
believe me if I told you.
Hey, hey!
Why did you do that?
Let your friends rest.
They'll be fine.
What comes next is for you
and you alone.
Hellboy, your story
whispered itself into my ear
and I realized
fate had something else
in store for us both.
- Okay.
- Tell me,
are there still tales
of King Arthur in your time?
How he drew the sword
from the stone?
Uh, yeah. Movies, too.
He's a regular
pop culture phenom.
Give me your hand.
People believe
that Arthur's lineage
died with him,
but it's not true.
The bloodline continued
when Arthur had a daughter
and that daughter
had a daughter, and so on.
Ending with
Sarah Bethany Hughes.
She used to fly to the Sabbath
on the back of a demon
in the shape of a goat.
And on Walpurgis Night, 1574,
she married that demon.
(SCREAMS)
That very night
she was taken down to hell,
where she delivered a son,
Anung un Rama.
That last part, I've heard
that before. What is that?
It's you...
Anung un Rama.
Destroyer of all things.
The title you were given
on the day you were born.
So, my mother was human.
And so are you.
At least in part.
Son of Arthur,
last of the royal lineage.
Blood of his blood.
Destined to be king of man.
Which is why
I know you are
the only one who can
do what must be done.
(RUMBLING)
Excalibur, the one weapon
that can stand against Nimue.
HELLBOY: Ah, looks bigger
in the cartoon.
Only a true descendant
of Arthur can wield it.
It is your birthright,
Hellboy, your destiny.
This is how you will destroy
the Blood Queen.
(DRAGON SCREECHING)
(ROARING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
(YELLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
No! You gave me your word!
Take the sword
before it's too late!
Take it!
Take it now!
You fool!
I used the last of my magic
to bring Excalibur here.
Now the sword
has returned to Arthur,
the only man worthy of it.
You could've stopped her.
At least I won't be here
to watch the world
wither and die.
(CROW CAWING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
GRUAGACH: Run!
Yeah, go on, run.
You pathetic bastards.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(GRUAGACH LAUGHS)
REPORTER: (ON TV) So far,
the British government
has failed to pinpoint
the origin of the plague
which is spreading
at an unprecedented rate.
The Prime Minister
has declared
an official state of emergency
and is urging British citizens
to remain indoors
and to avoid contact with
anyone who may be infected.
Casualties are expected to
reach 100,000 within two hours,
with the British plague
spreading to the EU
resulting in
massive fatalities
over the next 24 hours
and threatening to spark
a global epidemic.
Listen up, ladies and gentlemen.
The shit has gone
way beyond the fan.
Out there, there's
a fifth century sorceress
and her pig monster,
who want to bring down
the curtain
on London and the world.
Now, please tell me
where the fuck they are!
(BELL RINGING)
(SONG PLAYING ON SPEAKERS)
I need to see some ID, love.
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
(ON TV) The infection rate is
much higher than initially...
DAIMIO: You gonna tell us
what happened down there?
Where's Gandalf?
He's dead. He offered me
the sword, Excalibur.
He said it was the only way
to kill the Blood Queen.
All right,
so where is it?
HELLBOY:
I didn't take the sword.
'Cause if I do,
I'm the guy who's gonna
bring about the end
of the world.
You're the guy
who's going to
bring about
the end of the world?
Get over yourself.
Daimio!
- We've got a job to do.
- (CELL PHONE CHIMES)
We've got to go.
What's wrong?
The Blood Queen
just took out the B.P.R.D.
Dad.
(GRUNTS)
(ALARM BLARING)
(PANTING)
(EXHALES)
We'll find your father.
He's not dead.
Trust me, I'd know.
DAIMIO: Have a look at this.
REPORTER: (ON TV) I'm outside
St. Paul's Cathedral,
and right over there,
hundreds of armed police
continue a shootout
with an unknown assailant.
(TIRES SCREECH)
(SIREN BLARING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(DRAGONS SCREECHING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
POLICEMAN:
Get out of the way!
(ALL CLAMORING)
(GUN FIRES)
Hey! I'm on your side!
- Sorry. My bad.
- M-11!
No one enters
under any circumstances!
HELLBOY: Where is she?
Dad!
GRUAGACH: Hello, Hellboy.
Sorry my queen
couldn't be here
to greet you in person.
That's not a good sign.
ALICE: How did he get
so fucking big?
Hellboy, as you can see,
she's made sure you receive
a proper fucking welcome.
You've no idea how long
I've been waiting for this.
I have some idea!
You know, I was the guy
that sent little piggy squealing
all the way back home.
- (IMITATES SQUEALING)
- Take cover!
(ROARS)
I'll rip your fucking head off!
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS AND GROANS)
(ROARS)
(HELLBOY GRUNTS)
Look out! (SCREAMS)
(WINCES)
Little piggy, I brought
your favorite! Iron!
(LAUGHING)
That's not gonna
work this time.
It won't budge!
(GROANING)
(ROARING)
- (SCREAMS)
- Take that, you fucker!
Come here, you...
Fucking bastard.
(GRUNTING)
Get out of here.
- I'm not just gonna leave you!
- (GROANING)
Go! (GROANING)
GRUAGACH: Fuck off!
(SCREAMING)
(CRACKING)
(YELLS)
(STRAINING)
(GROWLING)
(BONES CRUNCHING)
(ROARS)
(GROANS)
Look at ya. You got a face
like a baboon's ass.
Now just lay there and bleed
while I finish you off.
Oh, yeah?
Good luck with that, pal!
(SNARLS)
Huh?
(SNARLING)
Fucking mutt.
- (GROWLING)
- Daimio?
- Let's eat some barbecue!
- (SNARLS)
- ALICE: Hellboy!
- HELLBOY: Whoa!
What am I supposed
to do with that?
ALICE: Improvise!
(GRUNTING)
I'm gonna squash
your fucking head now.
- Here, you red-faced twat!
- NIMUE: Enough!
Your Majesty.
Let him go, my pet.
We had a deal.
I found you.
I set all this in motion!
I was the beginning of it all.
And I am the end.
(CHOKING)
Forgive me. I needed someone
to challenge Hellboy,
push him to the edge.
(COUGHS)
But you promised!
To make you whole again.
Powerful beyond compare.
(SQUEALING)
And for one brief,
shining moment,
- you were.
- This ain't fair!
Fuck you, Hellboy!
HELLBOY: Yeah, fuck you back.
(GRUNTS) All right,
time to finish this.
But I don't want
to kill you.
We are not enemies.
We are bound together by fate!
Not this crap again, lady!
- (SCREAMS)
- Some lessons bear repeating.
(GROANS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
NIMUE: Just think
how many spent their lives
searching for Arthur's tomb.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
It's been right here
all along.
Go ahead.
It's yours by right.
You can feel it,
can't you?
How it calls to you.
Stirring the thing
at the core of your being.
The thing
you're destined to be.
Go ahead, take it.
You want to kill me,
don't you?
Pick up the sword.
Take it!
No!
I don't know
what your game is here,
but I'm done playing!
Very well.
(WHIMPERING)
Dad! Dad!
Don't worry about me.
You do what you have to do
and take out this bitch!
No! Nimue! Nimue, no!
Let him go, Nimue!
Let him go!
It's me you want! Take me!
I already have you.
You just don't know it yet.
No! No! No!
Dad!
Dad?
No. Please don't go.
(SHOUTING) No!
(GROANING)
Jesus Christ, mate.
You're a mess.
Well, at least
now I know why
you've been acting like
such a fucking dick.
I need you to pull it
together now!
He needs our help.
NIMUE: Save your tears.
His death is a mercy
compared to what
I have in store
for the rest of mankind.
All because you were
too cowardly to use Excalibur
when you had the chance.
Both your fathers
would be ashamed!
Nimue!
(STRAINING)
(YELLING)
(GASPS)
(GROWLING)
Come to me.
Come.
(RUMBLING)
(ROARING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(MAN SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
You're so beautiful.
Now you see that we were
born to rule together.
Arthur was just a man.
In his hands, Excalibur was
an instrument of death.
But in yours,
you can build a new world,
a better world
for all our kind.
My Lord.
BROOM: Stop!
This isn't you, Hellboy.
You're better than this.
Don't listen to this old fool.
You were meant for this.
She wants to use you,
make you into something
you're not.
So stop being
a whiny little shit
and show her she's wrong.
Go forth and embrace
your destiny.
Destroy your enemies!
BROOM: All this bitching
and moaning about destiny.
Grow a pair!
You're a man!
And a good one!
Act like it.
Don't let a prophecy
tell you who you are.
You decide for yourself.
He's lying!
You are the great beast
of the apocalypse.
This is the real you!
It always has been.
Burn out the past.
Be rid of the weakness.
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
My King.
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
(YELLING)
(PANTING)
This isn't over!
We are destined
for one another!
We will meet again
on the last day
of the ending of the world!
(LAUGHING)
Lady, quit while you're...
A head.
NIMUE: No! No!
(SCREAMING)
You knew, didn't you?
This whole time.
This beast inside me.
My inner nature!
My destiny!
So did you.
Why didn't you kill me
all those years ago?
You had a job,
to protect the world
from monsters!
I have never, ever
regretted the decision
I made that night.
Dad...
Shut up and listen to me.
There's things I need to say.
I tried to be
the best father I could.
What the hell did I know
about raising a kid?
I was a killer,
and damn good at it.
Some beasts deserved it,
some didn't.
But I did what I believed
was necessary.
And if I have any chance
of growing wings,
it's because of you.
(BREATH TREMBLES)
You changed me.
You changed everything.
And if there is ever an end
in this seemingly forever war,
it will be because of you
and your strong right hand.
You are mankind's best
and only hope, my boy.
Please. Please don't go.
I'm not ready.
Oh, yes, you are.
Being your father was
the best decision I ever made.
I love you, Hellboy.
(ECHOING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
ALICE: What's that?
A mistake.
(SHATTERS)
I like cats.
I've always been
more of a dog person.
ALICE: So, you're the king
of England now.
(CHUCKLES) Yup.
ALICE: Well, I didn't
see that coming.
HELLBOY: Okay,
yeah, we're here.
Does anybody copy?
Does any...
(SIGHS)
Worthless piece of crap!
- (THUDDING)
- (GROANS)
(ALICE GRUNTS)
(BLOWS)
Ah, the Oannes Society.
They make Osiris
look like Cub Scouts.
Christ!
Another secret boys club?
Bunch of lunatics.
What are they doing here?
And where's our back-up?
Ah! Come on!
Do not sneak up
on me like that!
Don't you ever
stop bitching?
I'm glad you could join us.
Yeah. Okay, come on,
let's get your game face on.
It's not something
I can just turn on and off
like a light switch.
The transformation is an electro-chemical
reaction to pain and emotional...
(GRUNTS)
I'm sorry to say,
it's a bit more complicated
than that... (GROANS)
Welcome to the B.P.R.D.
(IMITATES GROWLING)
Yeah, come on, let's do this.
(GRUNTING)
(BONES CRUNCHING)
(ROARING)
Ah, nobody told me
there was a dress code.
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
(GUN FIRES)
(GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
Hey, guys,
check it out.
"Icthyo Sapien."
Anyone know
what that means?
HELLBOY: (SINGING)
♪ Oh, Danny boy
(BURPS)
♪ The pipes
The pipes are call... ♪
I mean, it's fine,
you know.
It's like, we got the job done
and everything.
I put on a happy face.
But just feel, I don't know,
feels kinda...
THE LOBSTER:
I feel for you, kid.
The Professor was a good man.
Holy crap!
Listen.
You probably get this
all the time. And I don't...
I feel like such a jerk
doing this, you know?
But it's like,
I'm actually your biggest fan.
I... I... I've read about
everything you've done...
- Let me stop you right there.
- Okay.
I suppose you wanna
see the claw.
Yeah.
Oh, my God!
It's impressive.
You're telling me.
I don't think your old man would wanna
see you sitting around here moping.
- No, you're probably right.
- Gotta get back in the fight.
- Yeah.
- It's unfinished business.
- Yeah, okay.
- Got myself killed.
Well, it wasn't your fault.
- But listen.
- Yeah.
- Big one's coming.
- Okay.
You won a battle.
Now you gotta go
kick ass in the war.
I do?
Whoa! Okay! All right! Okay!
Now cut the shit,
buckle up,
get back in the fight.
I love you,
Lobster Johnson!
Okay.
Wow. All right,
that happened.
He mocks me!
And I've had enough!
Go! Kill Hellboy
and bring me his eye!
Can you do that?
MONSTER: I can.
And if I do?
I will grant you
your greatest wish.
MONSTER: And that is?
I will finally let you die.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
Sync by GoldenBeard